人人影视 原创翻译
后期  blueliongb
我们看戏  看厌了虚伪的表情
We've become bored with watching actors give us phony emotions.
看厌了花哨的特技
We're tired of pyrotechnics and special effects.
楚门的世界...
While the world he inhabits...
可以说是假的
Is, in some respects, counterfeit,
但楚门本人却半点不假
There's nothing fake about Truman himself.
这节目没有剧本  没有提词卡
No scripts. No cue cards.
虽未必是杰作  却是如假包换
It isn't always shakespeare, but it's genuine.
是生活的实录
It's a life.
我捱不住了
I'm not going to make it.
现场直播
你自己去吧  不要等我
You're going to have to go on without me.
楚门·伯班克饰演自己
老兄  怎可以
No way, mister.
你即使一拐一拐
You're going to the top of this mountain,
也得爬上山顶
Broken legs and all.
克里斯托创作
观众通宵收看  视他如良友
We find many viewers leave him on all night for comfort.
你发神经  知道吗
You're crazy, You know that?
吉尔·汉娜饰演梅莉
我的生活不分公私
Well, for me, There is no difference between a private life And a public life.
"真人表演"是我全部的生活
My life...is my life, is the Truman show.
"真人表演"是一种生活方式
The Truman show is... A lifestyle.
是高尚的生活
It's a noble life.
是一种...
It is...
美满的生活
a truly blessed life.
我还有什么不知道  你说吧
Yeah, tell me something I  don't   know.
好  你要答应我一件事
All right. Promise me one thing, though.
未到达山顶  而我死去...
If I die before I reach the summit,
你要把我当作粮食
You'll use me as an alternative source of food.
好恶心
Ew. Gross.
路易斯·克尔特林饰演马龙
内容真真实实  原原本本
It's all true. It's all real.
各位所见的  绝无虚假
Nothing here is fake. Nothing you see On this show is fake.
有的只是调控
It's merely controlled.
楚门的世界
吃掉我  我命令你
Eat me, damn it. That's an order.
也许只吃你的肚腩
Maybe just Your love handles.
我有肚腩
I have love handles?
有  小肚腩
Yeah. Little ones.
楚门  你快迟到了
Truman! You're going to be late.
知道了
Ok!
第10909日播映
早安
Good morning.
早安...
Morning. Morning.
假如再碰不见你们
Oh, and in case I don't see you,
祝你早  午  晚都安
Good afternoon, Good evening, and good night.
-早安  楚门 -早安  史宾沙
- Morning, Truman. - Morning, Spencer.
普鲁托  不要
Hey, pluto. No, no, no. Get down.
普鲁托不会咬你
Spencer: He won't hurt you.
我知道  但仍然怕
Get down. Ha ha. I know. It's just me.
来  普鲁托
Come on, pluto.
哦
Ohh!
老天
Holy cow.
这是什么
What is it?
现在新闻简报
Radio: here's a news flash just in.
一架客机飞经桃源岛上空时
An aircraft in trouble began shedding parts
发生故障  零件脱落
As it flew over seahaven just a few moments ago.
幸好没有击中人  各位可好
Wow. Luckily, No one was hurt. But, hey, How do you feel today?
正打算搭飞机
You thinking of Flying somewhere?
-不 -不  那就好了
- Nope. - No? Good.
行船走马三分险  何况搭飞机
This is classical clive with classical drive, So why don't you forget about the perils of flying,
现在播段音乐  帮你宁神镇惊
Settle back, and let this music calm you down?
一本"狗迷"  麻烦你
Dog fancy, please.
-谢谢 -多谢
- Thank you. - Thank you very much.
老岳  一份报纸  还有...
Ahh! Give me a paper there. Will you, Earl?
我要一本  太太爱看时装杂志
Oh, and, uh... One of these for the wife. Loves her fashion mags.
-还要什么  楚门 -统统齐全
- Will that be all for you, Truman? - That's the whole kit and caboodle.
再见
Catch you later. Ok.
早安
Morning.
汉克
Hey. Hank.
早安  楚门
Morning, Truman.
Good morning, Truman.
散养的凯撒鸡
你们好
Hey, how are you, guys?
-今天天气很好 -天天都这样好
- Beautiful day, isn't it? - Oh. Always.
-太太可好 -好  你们的呢
- Oh, and how's Your lovely wife? - Good, good. How about yours?
好极了...
Oh, couldn't be better.
跟你聊聊天挺好  楚门
Um, nice talking to you, Truman.
-跟你们聊天也挺好  -我们要赶时间
- You, too. - We must go now.
肯帮我买保险吗
Hey, think about That policy, huh?
买一送一  孪生子有特惠
Ok, that's 2 for 1. That's a good deal. Doppelganger special.
-老友  进去吗  -您先
- Hey, fellas. You going in? - Go ahead.
-请 -不  你先
- Hey. Go ahead. - No, you first, please.
谢了
Thans!
我不太心急进去
I'm not that anxious to get there.
楚门·伯班克
菲济群岛
Fiji islands.
楚门  你看
Truman, Did you see this?
桃源获选全球最佳居所
太太  抱歉 他如果昏迷就不能投保
Ha! Uh, I'm sorry, ma'am. If... if he's in a coma, He's probably uninsurable.
对  菲济  麻烦你
Hello? Yes. Uh, Fiji, please.
登记册有没有一位叫罗兰的人
Do you have a listing for lauren garland?
没有
Nothing listed?
叫西尔维亚·加兰的呢
Ok. Do you have a Sylvia Garland?
"S"开头的西尔维亚
"s" for Sylvia.
没有
Nothing?
谢谢
Ok. Thank you.
-劳伦斯 -楚门
- Lawrence. - Hey, burbank.
维园有一宗保险  我要你去成交
Got a prospect in wells park I need you to close.
维园
W-wells park?
在港岛那里
On, uh... harbor island?
还有别处吗
You know another one?
不行
Well, I can't do it.
我要见牙医  我的牙齿要补
I, uh, have an appointment. Dentist. Or... Yeah.
你卖不够保险  要补的不仅是牙齿
You're going to lose a lot more than your teeth if you don't meet your quota.
听着  楚门  公司打算月底裁员
Look, Truman. They're making cutbacks at the end of this month.
裁员
Cutbacks?
这宗生意你一定要做成
Yeah. Now, you need this.
顺便去吹吹海风  对你有益
Besides, a half hour across the bay, a little sea air... would do you good.
谢谢
Hey, thanks.
港岛渡轮码头
渡轮还没开出
Hello. Ferry still here, huh?
我以为错过了
Thought I might have missed it.
单程还是来回
One-way or return?
来回
Return.
你的票
There you go, sir.
可以帮你吗
Do you need any help, sir?
你走吧  我没事
You go ahead. I'll... I'll be fine.
亲爱的
Hi, honey.
超级市场有赠品  看
Look what I got free at the checkout.
叫"厨师良伴"
It's a chef's pal.
剁  磨  削  一物多用
It's a dicer, grater, peeler... all in one.
不会钝  可以用洗碗碟机洗
Never needs sharpening, dishwasher safe.
哇  真神奇
Wow! That's amazing.
楚门
Truman...
剪漏了一块
You missed a spot.
这才算是啤酒
That  is a beer.
马龙  我想离开
You know, I'm thinking about getting out, marlon.
离开  离开什么
Yeah? Out of what?
离开我的工作  离开桃源岛
Out of my job, out of seahaven.
你想辞工  为什么
Off this island. Out. Out of your job? What the hell's wrong with your job?
你的工作舒舒服服  只处理文件
You have a great job, Truman. You have a desk job.
我很羡慕
I'd kill for a desk job.
到你
Here you go.
想改行做杂货
You should try stocking vending machines for a living.
-不想  -杂货够刺激
- No, thanks. - Now, there's excitement.
你从没兴趣到外面走走
Don't you ever get antsy? Itchy feet?
走到哪里
Where's there to go?
菲济
Fiji.
菲济在哪里  靠近佛罗里达
Where the hell's Fiji? Near florida?
看见吗
See here?
我们在这里
Yeah. This is us...
绕个圈...
And all the way around here...
菲济
Fiji.
再走远一点  就回来
You can't get any further away before you start coming back.
菲济有些岛屿是没有人到过的
You know, there are still islands in Fiji where no human being has ever set foot.
那么  你打算几时去
So, when are you going to go?
要去  并不简单
It's not that simple.
需要钱  筹备
It takes... money, planning.
不能说走就走
I can't just up and go.
对
Right.
但我会去  一定会
I'm going to do it. Don't worry about that.
公司很快派发分红
Bonus time is just around the corner.
来喝杯酒吗
Hey, you coming for a drink?
今晚不行
No. I can't tonight.
似乎快有风暴  划回去吧
I don't like the look of that weather, son. I think we should head back.
-爸  多划一会  -应该回去了
- Oh, no, dad. Not yet. - No, come on. We should go back.
多划一会嘛  好吗
A bit farther. Listen... Please?
好吧
Ok.
爸
Daddy!
像只落汤鸡  去过哪里
You're soaked. Where have you been?
如果筹到八千元...
I figure if we can scrape together 8,000...
每次跟马龙玩完后..
Every time you and marlon get together
就可节俭  到处旅行一年
We can bum around the world for a year on that.
然后打回原形  不名一文
And then what, Truman? We'd be where we were 5 years ago.
你不现实得像个少年
You're talking like a teenager.
也许我的心境像少年
Well, maybe I feel like a teenager.
我们要供房子  楚门
We have mortgage payments, Truman.
还要供车
We have car payments.
不能一走了之  置财务责任于不顾
What, we're just going to walk away from our financial obligations?
会好刺激
It would be an adventure.
我们不打算生儿育女吗
I thought we were going to try for a baby.
还不够刺激
Isn't that enough of an adventure?
儿女可迟点生  我想出外走走
That can wait.
见见世面  闯新天地
I want to get away... See some of the world
楚门  闯新天地...
Honey, you want to be an explorer?
这种冲动谁都有过
This'll pass.
但迟早会明白不切实际
We all think like this now and then.
先脱掉湿衫裤  好不好
Let's get you out of these wet clothes, hmm?
上床吧
Come to bed.
每逢上床
You never See anything anyway.
镜头必定移开  播放音乐
They always... Turn the camera and play music and...
风吹帘动  观众什么都看不见
You know, The wind blows in, and the curtains move, and you don't See anything.
-"狗迷"  麻烦你  -好的
- Dog Fancy, please. - Dog Fancy.
谢谢
Thank you.
老岳  报纸
Paper, earl, please. Paper.
顺便要份时装杂志
Oh...I might as well pick one of these up.
-给太太的  -少不得
- For the wife? - She's got to have them.
-还要什么  -统统齐全
- Anything else, Truman? - That's the whole ball of wax.
再见
Catch you later.
爸
Dad?
你们干什么
Ohh! Hey, what are you doing?
究竟...
Hey! What the...
让开
Get out of the way!
截住他们
Stop them!
Stop those people!
停
Stop! Stop!
打开门  停车
Hey! Open the doors! Somebody stop the bus!
停下巴士...
Stop the bus!
停车
Somebody stop it!
很有趣对吧
And wasn't it funny...
一点也不出奇
It doesn't sound insane at all, Truman.
我经常见到你爸爸的影子
I see him 10 times a week in a hundred different faces.
上星期四  我差点抱错了人
I almost hugged a perfect stranger In the salon last thursday.
我明明见到爸爸
It was dad.
他样子像个流浪汉
I swear. Dressed like a homeless man.
最不可思议的是...
And you know what else was strange?
一个商人和一个拉着狗的女人
A businessman and a woman with a little dog
突然出现  把他推上巴士
came out of nowhere and forced him onto a bus.
市政局早应该驱逐流浪汉
Well, it's about time they cleaned up the trash downtown
否则本地也会乱七八糟
Before we become just like the rest of the country.
爸爸的尸体一直打捞不到
They never found Dad's body.
-也许他们... -天啊
- Maybe somehow - Oh, god.
我见到的  是他的孪生兄弟
I'm telling you, if it wasn't him, it was his twin.
爸爸有没有兄弟
Did dad have A brother?
楚门  你很清楚爸爸是个独子
Truman, you know perfectly well. That your father was an only child.
像你一样
Just like you.
楚门... 你爸爸淹死  你觉得内疚
Now, sweetie... You're just feeling bad because of what happened.
你把船向风暴驶去
You sailing off into that storm.
但我从来没有怪你
But I've never blamed you, Truman...
一向都不怪你
And I don't blame you now.
楚门
Truman?
你在地下室干什么
What are you doing down here?
修理剪草机
Fixing the mower.
今天我见到爸爸
Saw my father today.
我知道
I know.
你妈妈打过电话来
Your mother called.
你不应该触动她的伤心事
You really shouldn't upset her like that.
找我干什么
Did you want... What did you want?
我煮了通心粉
I made macaroni.
我不饿
I'm not hungry.
我们应该扔掉那剪草机
You know...You really ought to throw out that mower.
买一台爱奇牌剪草机吧
Get one of those new elk rotaries.
他在干什么
What's he doing?
她虽然被带走  但他对她念念不忘
See, they got rid of her, but they couldn't erase the memory.
不忘谁
The memory of who?
节目播送第10910日
-你没事吧  -你呢
- Whoa. Ow! OK? - You OK? All right?
-我撞倒你  对不起  -不要紧
- I'm so sorry I fell on you like that. - It's ok.
-我失魂落魄  -不要紧
- I'm just... I've been such a klutz all day. - It's all right.
我必定扭伤了脚踝
Sprained this ankle. Oh, my goodness.
摔在你身上  对不起
Oh, I'm so sorry. I'm so sorry to fall on you like that.
不要紧  不用介意
Oh, that's all right. Don't worry about it.
-我叫梅莉  -我叫楚门
- I'm Meryl. - Hi. I'm Truman.
幸会...
Hey. Nice to meet you.
楚门  你太用功了
Truman, you've studied enough.
我要记熟
No. I got to commit this to memory.
一起去喝杯冰冻啤酒
Come on, Truman, one ice-cold brewski.
来吧
Come on.
你要小心  你抄我  我错你就错
Come on. You're going to have to copy off me, so be careful.
我知道
I know it.
楚门  你比我老实  再见
No? You're a better person than I am.
再见...
See you later.
再见  傻瓜
Bye. See you later, loser.
你好
Hi
你说什么
Konnichi-wa.
你在学日文
Oh. You take japanese.
对了
Oh, yes. Yeah.
你叫罗兰  对吗
Lauren, right?
上面写着...
It's on the...
罗兰  对
Lauren. Right, right.
我叫楚门
I'm Truman burbank.
我知道
Yeah. I... I know.
他们不准我跟你交谈
you know, I'm not allowed to talk to you.
真的
Really?
可以明白  我是个危险人物
Yeah. Well, I can understand that. I'm a pretty dangerous character.
对不起  我作不了主
I'm sorry. It's not up to me.
女儿家当然要小心
A girl's got to be careful.
你有男朋友  对不对
You have a boyfriend, right?
不是因为男朋友
No, it's not that.
因为跟我一起那小姐
Was it Meryl, that girl that was with me?
我们...  只是普通朋友
We're not... we don't... We're not... we're just... We're friends.
不是因为她
It's nothing like that.
因为我的样子不合眼缘
It's how I look? Not your type?
不
No.
我喜欢你的襟章
I like your pin.
怎样收场
我自己也不知道
I was wondering that myself.
你愿不愿意...
Mmm. Would you want to... maybe possibly...
陪我上街  去吃薄饼
Sometime go out for some pizza or something?
星期五
Like, friday?
-星期六  -我不能
- Saturday? - I can't.
星期天  星期一  星期二
Sunday, Monday, Tuesday?
现在
明天是期终考试
We have finals tomorrow.
我知道
Yeah, I know.
我们现在不去  以后没有机会
If we don't go now, it won't happen.
明白吗
Do you understand?
你认为怎样
So, what do you want to do?
不要把手伸出车外
Please keep your hands inside the car!
这是我最喜欢吃薄饼的地方
This is my favorite pizza place.
东尼  来个大薄饼  多加点水藻
Tony! One large, extra plankton.
我们时间无多  他们快来了
We have so little time. They're going to be here any minute.
-谁  -他们不想我和你交谈
- Who are? - They don't want me talking to you.
那就别交谈好了
Then don't talk.
他们来了
They're here.
-楚门  -他们想怎样
- Truman. - What do they want?
听我说  人人都清楚你的一切
Listen to me. Everybody knows about you. Everybody knows everything you do.
人人都在假装  明白吗
They're pretending, Truman. Do you understand? Everybody's pretending.
-我不明白... -不...  我不是罗兰
- Lauren, I don't know... - No, my name's not lauren.
我叫西尔维亚
It's Sylvia. My name's Sylvia.
-西尔维亚  -是的
- Sylvia? - Yeah.
罗兰  你又来了
Lauren, sweetheart, not again.
等等  你是谁
Hey, wait a minute. Who are you?
-她的爸爸  -什么
- I'm her father! - What?
-我没见过他  -我们没做什么
- I've never even Seen him before. - We didn't do anything.
-乖女儿  我们走吧  -他撒谎
- Honey, please. - He's lying.
别信他  我说的话都是真的
Truman, please, Don't listen to him. Everything I've told you is the truth.
这是假的  是为你而设的
This, it's fake. It's all for you.
-我不明白  -什么都是虚构的
- I don't understand. - The sky and the sea, Everything... it's a set.
是做戏  人人在看你  别信他
It's a show. Everybody's watching you. Please don't listen to him.
他会骗你  小心
He's gonna lie to you. They're watching us now.
-究竟什么事  -精神分裂
- What's going on? - Schizophrenia. She has episodes.
-求求你  不要  -我们已经尽量医她
- Please. Oh, no! - We've tried everything.
别担心  你不是第一个
Don't worry. You're not the first.
-不要听他的  -她把所有男朋友都带来这里
- Truman! - She brings all her boyfriends down here.
他在说什么  楚门  他在骗你
What's he saying? Truman, he's lying!
你要逃出去  逃出去找我
Get out of here. Come and find me.
我们在学校再见
Don't worry.
我们要搬去菲济
Fiji. We're moving to Fiji.
菲济
Fiji?
西尔维亚
Sylvia!
他为什么不跟她去菲济
Why didn't he just follow her to Fiji?
他妈妈患了大病
His mother got sick, really sick.
他孝顺  不忍心离开  也许太孝顺了
He couldn't leave her. He's kind. Maybe he's too kind.
他失去罗兰不久  就娶了梅莉
I can't believe he married Meryl on the rebound.
对不起
Excuse me.
我们已有那段剧情的影带
Come on, sal. We've already got this on the greatest hits tape.
可以借给我吗
Can I borrow that?
怎样收场
有几分相像  但不全像
Close, but no cigar.
世外桃源又一天
Radio announcer: And it's another beautiful day in paradise, folks
但大家要记着  系上安全带
But don't forget to buckle up out there in radio land.
等候提示
Wait for the cue. Wait for the cue.
准备出动
Stand by, one.
他沿史超活道西行  临记准备
He's heading west on stewart.
90秒后  他会到达
Stand by, all extras. He'll be on you in about 90 seconds.
记得放小狗出来
Props, make sure the coffee's hot.
他转入兰嘉士打广场
Ok, he's making his turn onto lancaster square.
兰嘉士打广场
惨  他差点撞倒人
Aah! Man on radio: oh, my god. He nearly hit her.
更改频率
Something's wrong. Change frequencies.
抱歉  我们忙中有错
Ouch. Sorry about that, folks.
刚才无意中播放了警察电台
I guess we picked up a police frequency or something. It sometimes happens, and it can drive you crazy.
现在是贾礼金曲时间
Ok, it's classical clive back in here,
我们为你准备了精彩的音乐
And we've still got some great music up ahead,
但大家记紧  扣好安全带
But hey, don't forget to buckle up. Remember safety.
小心驶得万年船  对不对
A good driver is a safe driver. A safe driver is what?
驱逐流浪汉  桃源岛长老忍无可忍
我喜欢这个想法
I love that idea.
这很酷吧
It's pretty cool, isn't it?
是啊  我喜欢
Yeah, I love it.
有何贵干
Can I help?
我约见了基宝企业
Yeah. I have an appointment at gable enterprises.
不可能
That's impossible.
-什么事  -没什么
- What's happening? - Nothing.
说  什么事
Just tell me What's happening.
请离开  现在正装修
Got to go, sir. We're remodeling.
不是  他们是什么人
No, you're not. What are those people doing back there?
不关你事...
It's none of Your business.
你不说  我去报警
If you don't tell me what's Happening, I'll report you!
你擅闯他人地方
You're trespassing.
马龙
Marlon!
楚门  什么事
Truman. What are you Doing here?
我想说句话
I gotta talk to you.
我现在没有空...
It's a bad time, ok? I'm way behind.
有些不寻常的事  很不寻常
I'm onto something, marlon. Something big.
你面色发青
You ok? You look like shit.
-我可能惹上麻烦  -什么麻烦
- I think I'm mixed up in something. - Mixed up in what?
很难解释
There's no point Trying to explain it
总之千奇百怪
But a lot of strange things Have been happening.
升降机里面有人  却没有墙
The people on the elevator. There was no backing on it.
我看过去  看到人
I looked out. There was people there.
我上班途中  听收音机
And on the radio on the way to work,
我一举一动  收音机直接播放
It starts following me along, talking about everything that I'm doing.
-明白吗  -你想象力太丰富了
- You know what I mean? - Truman, look, this is One of your fantasies.
-这事跟我爸爸有关  -你爸爸
- I think this is about my dad. - Your dad?
他可能依然活着
I think he's alive.
一定有人在跟踪我
Yeah. I'll tell you about it later. I'm definitely being followed.
谁在跟踪你
Who?
很难说  似乎是普通人
It's hard to tell. They look just like regular people.
这两个呢
How about those two?
不知道  有可能
I don't know. Could be.
我一有突发举动  他们就...
It's when I'm unpredictable, That's... they can't...
-有没有事情发生  -没有
- Did anything happen? - No.
跟我走  行吗
Mm-hmm. We gotta get out of here.
-准备好了吗  -不行
- You ready to go? - No.
- 我才刚来这里  -快点  快点
- No. I just came here. - Come on, come on, come on!
我告诉你我不能
I told you I can't.
我们都会被炒鱿鱼
You're gonna get both our asses Fired. You know that.
-无所谓  -什么
- Ok, man, Let's do it. - What?
你要怎样就怎样
Whatever you say. I'm game.
你在说什么
Marlon: what are you talking about?
对了  你的生日一年只有一次
Yes, siree. Your birthday comes but once a year.
我可能受到别人操纵
Maybe I'm being set up for something.
你有没有这种感觉
You ever think about that, marlon?
好像一生都身不由己
Like your whole life has been building towards something?
没有
Mmm, no.
那年夏天  你替凯撒运鸡...
When you were hauling chickens In the summer for kaiser
离开过桃源岛  到过哪里
What was The furthest you ever got off the island?
什么地方都到过  但都不及这里
Went all over. Never found a place like this, though.
看看这日落  楚门
Look at that sunset, Truman.
瑰丽无比
It's perfect.
对  上帝的杰作
Yeah. That's the big guy.
简直鬼斧神工
Quite a paintbrush he's got.
是啊
Yup.
你不要告诉别人
Just between you and me, marlon...
我打算外出走走
I'm going away for a while.
真的
Really?
嗯
Yeah.
小天使
Oh, little angel.
小笑弹
Oh, my little clown.
红萝卜
Old carrot top.
最好的照片
The best photos.
应该送你回家了
We should be getting you home, mother.
等等 我们在伟人石像前拍的照片
Hold on a minute. Here's us at mount rushmore.
记得吗  你的爸爸当时还在世
Do you remember, Truman, When dad was still with us?
车程很远  你一直在车里睡
That was quite a drive. You slept the whole way there.
石像看来很小
It looks so small.
回忆里的东西总比真实的小
Things always do when you look back, darling.
你看  那是我们最快乐的一天
Oh, look, Truman. The happiest day of our lives.
看  珍  茱迪  钟安
Oh, look. Jean, Jodie, Joanne.
她多漂亮  对不对
Doesn't she look beautiful, Truman?
仍然漂亮
Well, she still does.
还有很多空页可以贴小孩照片
And there's lots of pages left over for baby photos.
我希望有生之年能抱孙子
I would like to hold a grandchild in my arms before I go.
-我们应该送你回家  -我送她
- Angela, we really should be getting you home. - I'll take her.
不... 你坐着  休息一下
No, no, no. You stay, relax.
你喜欢的节目快播映了
Enjoy yourself. Your favorite show will be coming on.
况且  梅莉和我有些话想说
Besides, we have something to discuss.
关于某人的生日
A certain person's birthday.
明白了
Oh, I see.
明天继续收看"我爱露丝"
And there'll be another episode Of  I love lucy same time tomorrow.
现在是"怀旧名片"时间
But right now it's time for golden oldies.
今晚我们播映脍炙人口的...
Tonight, we present the enduring, much-loved classic
"归心似箭"
Show me the way to go home.
本片歌颂小镇生活
A hymn of praise to small-town life,
令我们体验到在家千日好
Where we learn that you don't have to leave home
故乡的浓厚人情味
To discover What the world's all about, and that no one is poor who has friends.
悲欢离合  笑中有泪
Full of laughter and love, pain and sadness,
迷途知返
But ultimately redemption,
我们见证柯家的奋斗
We share the trials and tribulations of the abbott family.
毕朗奴饰演叔叔  感人肺腑
Note the touching performance of ronald brierly as uncle buddy.
那碗樱桃的一幕
And that scene with the bowl of cherries is gonna
保证各位捧腹
have you splitting your sides with laughter all over again.
大卫  珍妮花重逢  赚人热泪
And there'll be tears, too, when david and jennifer are reunited.
我不再多讲
But enough from me.
现在就送上锦丹村的柯家
Let's join the abbotts in camden village.
楚门  谢谢你
Oh. Thank you, sweetie.
跟我到外面去  我有话想说
I need to talk to you, But let's go outside.
我很想听  但要赶时间
Oh, sweetie, I'd love to, But I'm really late.
到哪里去
What's your rush?
做手术
Surgery.
升降机发生意外  新闻有报导
There was that elevator disaster downtown. It was on the news last night.
钢缆断了
This cable just snapped.
从十楼跌下
This elevator, It just plummeted down 10 flights.
乘客非死则伤
The non-union workers.
那部升降机在你公司附近
Just monsters. You know, that building, It's right next door to where you work.
幸好你没有搭
Can you imagine if you had been in there?
否则不堪设想
It's not even worth thinking about.
有位女乘客要做切肢手术
Anyway, I have an amputation on one of the young women in that elevator.
她很年轻的  真不幸
She's very young. It's very sad.
祝我顺利吧
Anyway, wish me luck.
我会叠手指  祝你顺利
I'll cross my fingers for you.
对不起... 请问你什么事
Uh, excuse me. Hi, excuse me. May I help you?
我太太梅莉是这里的护士
Oh, uh... Yes. I'm looking for my wife, Nurse Burbank.
我有急事要找她
It's very important.
不可以  她要做手术
I'm afraid that that's not possible. She's in pre-op.
替我传个口讯  行吗
Sure. Ok, fine. Can you pass along a message?
我会试试
I'll try.
我要去菲济  抵达后会致电给她
Can you tell her I had to go to Fiji and that I'll call her when I get there?
抵达菲济后
When you... when you get to Fiji?
对了
You got it.
我会告诉她
Fine. I'll tell her.
非常感激
Thank you so much.
-对不起  -不要紧
- Sorry. - It's ok.
我帮你
I'll help you
他来了
He's here.
我知道
I know, I know. Shh, shh, shh.
解剖刀
Scalpel.
我现在在右膝上...
I'm now making my primary incision
做初步切割
Just above the right knee.
按着她
Hold her
割得恰到好处
Nicely done.
没什么好看  除非你是家属
This isn't going to be pretty.
你手术的确高明
It's just Beautiful. Beautiful job.
让其他人来收拾吧
I'll just let someone else tidy up here.
乘客留意
可能发生在你身上
-要你等  对不起  -不要紧
- I'm sorry to keep you. - Oh, that's ok.
可以效劳吗
How can I help?
一张去菲济的机票
I would like to book a flight to Fiji.
几时出发
When would you like to leave?
今天
Today.
抱歉  起码要一个月后才有位
I'm sorry. I don't have anything for at least a month.
一个月后
A month?
现在是旺季
It's the busy season.
要不要订位
You want to book the flight?
不要了  我试试其他交通工具
It doesn't matter. I'll make other arrangements, ok?
往芝加哥乘客  请即上车
Last call for chicago!
所有乘客上车
All aboard!
谢谢
Thank you.
风中之城芝加哥  我们来也
Windy city, here we come.
你好
Hi. Hi.
Hello.
修女
Sisters.
妈妈  那个人是不是...
Hey, mom, isn't that...
看前面  乖女儿
Shh. Face the front.
各位下车  机件故障
Everybody off. We've got a problem.
对不起  小伙子
I'm sorry, son.
他的爸爸是芝加哥人  对吗
His father was from Chicago, wasn't he?
不... 他的牙医是佛罗里达人
No. His dentist was from pensacola.
他爸爸是爱荷华人
His father was from des moines.
为什么去芝加哥
But how come he wants to go to chicago?
他不想去  哪里也不想去
He's not going to chicago. He's not going anywhere.
只是和梅莉斗气
He has to have it out with Meryl.
楚门
Truman?
你没事吧
Honey, are you ok?
上车
Get in.
楚门
Truman.
看
Look.
什么
What? Shh.
待会儿将会见到...
I predict that in just a moment
一位太太骑着红色单车
We will see a lady on a red bike,
然后有个人拿着鲜花
Followed by a man with flowers
跟着有架黄色甲虫型福士
And a volkswagen beetle with a dented fender.
-楚门  拜  你  -看
- Truman, please. - Look.
太太
Lady...
鲜花
Flowers...
然后呢
And...
楚门  太荒谬了
Truman, this is silly.
来了
There it is! There it is!
一架黄色福士
There's that dented Beetle! Yes!
知道我怎么猜中的吗
Don't you want to know how I did that?
很简单  他们在兜圈
I'll tell you. They're on a loop.
沿着附近几条街  不断兜圈
They go around the block. They come back.
团团转
They go around again. They just go round and round. Round and round.
我请了马龙夫妇周日来烧烤
I invited rita and marlon for a barbecue on sunday.
我不会在这里
I won't be here Sunday.
记得提醒我买炭
And I need you to remind me That we need more charcoal.
我的话你有没有听见
Are you listening to a word I'm saying?
你讲来讲去  都要去菲济
You're upset because You want to go to Fiji. Is that it?
去吧
Ok, ok, go.
但应该储几个月的生活费才去
I think you should save for a few months and then go. There.
现在满意了没有
Are you happy now?
我想去洗个澡
I want to go take a shower.
我们现在就去
Let's go now.
我现在可以去了
I'm ready to go now. Why wait?
坐言起行  早走早着  对不对
Early bird gathers no moss. Rolling stone catches the worm, right?
你在干什么
Truman, What are you doing?
楚门
Truman!
应该开到哪里去
Where shall we go? Where shall we go?
楚门  我们去哪里
Truman, where are we going?
我只是漫无目的  顺其自然
I don't really know. I guess I'm being spontaneous.
不得了  我顺其自然起来
Somebody help me! I'm being spontaneous!
不去菲济了  反正开车到不了
Truman. Forget Fiji. can't very well drive to Fiji, can we?
不如去大西洋城
What about Atlantic city?
不要去  你讨厌赌博
Oh, no, you hate to gamble.
-的确讨厌  -为什么还去
- That's right, I do, don't I? - So why would you want to go there?
因为没去过
Because I never have.
观光就是去没去过的地方
That's why people go places, isn't it?
楚门  我想呕吐
Truman, Truman, I think I'm gonna throw up.
我也想
Me, too.
到处都塞车
Blocked at every turn.
配合得天衣无缝  对吗
Beautifully synchronized, don't you agree?
连塞车你也怪我
You're blaming me for the traffic?
应该吗
Should I?
楚门  我们回家吧
Truman... Let's go home.
好  塞车可能塞几个钟头
You're right. We could be stuck here for hours.
一直塞到大西洋城  回去吧
It could be like this all the way to atlantic city. Let's go back.
我一时糊涂  不应该去
I'm sorry. I don't know what got into me.
可以开慢一点吗
Can you please slow down?
可以
Yes, I can.
-你忘记转弯  -我又改变主意
- Truman! Truman! That's our turn off! - I changed my mind again.
新奥尔良这几天应该好热闹
What's new orleans like this time of year?
是狂欢节
Mardi gras! Whoo! Ha ha ha!
看  同一条路  一部车都没有
Look, Meryl, same road, no cars.
像魔术一样
It's magic. Ha ha ha!
我要下车  你的脑袋有毛病
You let me out. You're not right in the head.
你要自毁  自毁到够
You want to destroy yourself, do it on your own.
我要人陪
I think I'd like a little company.
楚门  你明知故犯
Oh, Truman... You knew this would happen.
明知道自己不敢开车过海
You know you can't drive over water.
回家吧  你会觉得安全
Let's go home where you'll feel safe.
-伸手过来  -楚门
- Give me your hand. Sweetie...
你转弯
Drive.
楚门
Truman!
不可以  这样做是犯法
We shouldn't be doing this! We're breaking the law!
惨
Oh, my! You can do it!
不要
Please, don't!
-你办得到  -楚门
- You can make it! - Truman!
过了桥  我们过了桥...
Aah! Oh, we're over! We're over the bridge! We're over the bridge!
-过了吗  -我们过了桥...
- We're over? We're over the bridge. - We're over the bridge.
我们过了桥
We're over!
山火警告: 极度危险
-有山火  -骗人  别怕
- Truman! What about that sign? - They're exaggerating. We'll be fine.
你不相信吗
Exaggerating? Do you believe that?
着火了...  楚门
Oh, my! Oh, my! Truman, we're on fire!
只是烟雾...
It's ok. We're on fire! It's ok. It's just smoke.
-你没事吧  -没事
- You ok? - Yes.
-想再试吗  -不想
- Want to do it again? - No! Ha ha ha ha!
楚门  停车
Truman, stop! Oh, god!
我们没有钱  到新奥尔良怎么办
Oh! So, what are we going to do for money When we get to new orleans?
我有桃源的银行卡
I have my seahaven bank card.
你打算动用储蓄
We're just going to eat Into our savings, is that it?
一到达  我要打电话给你妈妈
I'm going to have to call your mother when we get there.
她一定担心得要命
She's going to be worried sick.
可能受不起打击
I don't know how she's going to take this.
又有什么事
What now?
红色警报  红色警报
Red alert! This is a red alert!
桃源核电站
楚门  看起来是工厂核泄露
Truman, it looks like a leak at the plant.
掉头  核电厂辐射泄露  要关闭
Back up! Back up! Leak at the plant. We had to shut her down.
核电厂似乎辐射泄露
可不可以绕路
Is there Any way around?
全区都要疏散
Whole area's Being evacuated.
-要我帮忙吗  -不用
- Is there anything I can do? - No, ma'am.
-谢谢你  -不用客气  楚门
- Thank you for your help. - You're welcome, Truman.
楚门
Truman.
Truman! Truman!
楚门... 回来
Truman, come back!
楚门  截住他
Truman! Truman! Stop him!
楚门
Unh! Truman!
不要走过来
Stay away!
不要...
Unh! Aah!
麻烦了你们  很不好意思
Thank you both so much for your help. I really appreciate it.
这次放过他  下次我们要检控
He's lucky to be alive, ma'am. Next time, we'll have to file charges.
我明白
I understand.
-再次谢谢你们  晚安  -晚安
- Thanks again. - Good night.
你需要接受治疗
Let me get you some help, Truman.
你有病
You're not well.
为什么要替我生孩子
Why do you want to have a baby with me?
你不喜欢我
You can't stand me.
不是的
That's not true.
我去倒杯莫可可给你
Why don't you let me fix you some of this new mococoa drink?
尼加拉瓜山天然可可炼制
All natural cocoa beans From the upper slopes of mount nicaragua.
不含人工糖分
No artificial sweeteners.
你在说什么
What the hell are you talking about?
跟谁说话
Who are you talking to?
各种可可中  莫可可最好喝
I've tasted other cocoas. This is the best.
跟我们有什么关系
What the hell does this have to do with anything?
究竟什么事
Tell me what's happening!
你还问  你自己精神崩溃
You're having a nervous breakdown, that's what.
你有份  对不对
You're part of this, aren't you?
-楚门  -梅莉
- Truman! - Meryl!
你吓到了我
You... are... scaring me!
你才吓到了我
No, you're scaring me, Meryl.
你打算怎样处置我
What are you going to do?
剁  切  削
Dice me? Slice me and peel me?
多种选择
There are so many choices!
快想想办法
Aah! Do something!
你说什么
What? What did you say?
你跟谁说话
Who are you talking to?
我没有说话  什么也没说
Nothing. I didn't say anything. I didn't say anything.
-你有  -我没有
- You said, "do something." - No, I didn't. I wasn't talking to anybody.
-告诉我  -我毫不知情  停手
- Talk to me! - I don't know anything! Please stop!
不要动
[banging]Stay where You are!
楚门
Truman?
谢天谢地
Oh, thank god! Oh, thank god!
叫我怎么忍受下去
How can anyone expect me to carry on under these conditions?
完全没有专业精神
It's unprofessional!
不要怕
Shh, it's ok.
没事  不要怕
Everything's gonna be ok.
会好起来的
It's all gonna be fine.
我脑袋一片混乱
I don't know what to think, marlon.
快要疯了
Maybe I'm losing my mind, but...
全世界似乎绕着我而转
It feels like the whole world revolves around me somehow.
即是说  你自以为好重要
That's a lot of world for one man, Truman.
不是有点一厢情愿吗
Sure that's not wishful thinking?
你感觉郁郁不得志
You wishing you'd made something more out of yourself?
不得志是很正常的感觉
Come on, who hasn't sat in the john,
谁也希望踌躇满志
Had an imaginary interview on seahaven tonight?
谁也希望做个名人
Who hasn't wanted to be somebody?
我的意思是人人都似乎在串谋
This is different. Everybody seems to be in on it.
你七岁时  我们已经是老朋友
I've been your best friend Since we were 7 years old.
读书考试  你抄我
The only way you and I ever Made it throug
我抄你
school was by cheating off each other's test papers.
你我的答案一模一样
Jesus, they were identical.
我总觉得安全
But I always felt safe knowing that.
因为无论答对还是答错
'Cause whatever the answer was,
我们都能够一同对  一同错
We were right together and we were wrong together.
那一晚去露营  通宵不睡
Remember when I stayed up all night in your tent
因为你要扮北极
'Cause you wanted to play north pole?
搞到我得肺炎
And I got pneumonia?
记得吗
You remember that?
你要向学校请了一个月的病假
You were out of school for about a month.
你我亲如兄弟
You're the closest thing I ever had to a brother.
我知道...
I know that things...
你我的人生都不算顺利
Haven't really worked out for either of us
离理想相当远
Like we used to dream they would.
觉得时不与我
I know that feeling, when it's like everything's slipping away...
你无法面对现实  于是...
You don't want to believe it
疑神疑鬼
So you look for answers somewhere else, but...
但我肯为你这朋友  两胁插刀
Well... the point is... I'd gladly walk in front of traffic for you.
Well... the point is, I would gladly step in front of traffic for you, Truman.
怎么也不会欺骗你
And the last thing I'd ever do is lie to you.
怎么也不会...
And the last thing that I would ever do...
欺骗你
Is lie to you.
你不妨想一想
I mean, think about it, Truman.
假如人人都串谋
If everybody is in on it...
即是说  我也串谋
I'd have to be In on it, too.
我没有串谋  楚门  因为...
I'm not in on it, Truman, because...
根本没有这回事
There is no "It."
但有一件事你是对的
You were right about one thing, though.
什么事
What's that?
这场风波的起因
The thing that started all this.
我替你找到他
Yep. I found him for you, Truman.
所以我今晚来找你
That's why I came by tonight.
他必定有很多话要说
I'm sure he's got quite a story to tell.
你过去吧
Go to him.
烟雾不要太浓
Easy on the fog.
吊臂摄影机准备
Stand by, crane cam.
吊臂摄影机
Crane cam.
按摄影机三号
Button cam 3.
我一直都相信你没遇难
I never stopped believing.
用广角镜  路边摄影机八号
And wide, curb cam 8.
乖儿子
My son! Oh!
-要不要特写  -暂时不要
- Move in For a closeup? - No, no, no.
等一下
Move back and...
加强配乐
Fade up music.
现在特写
And now go in close.
这么多年  白白过去
All those years wasted.
我会弥补你的损失
I'll make it up to you, son.
一定会
I swear.
爸爸
Dad.
好
Yes!
很精彩
Bravo. That was a really great experience.
恭喜
Congratulations.
大家静一点  留神
Ok, quiet down. Let's concentrate.
干得好
That was good work.
开香槟庆祝
Let's get some champagne up here.
克里斯托  太精彩了
Congratulations. Brilliant, Christof. Just brilliant.
多么感人肺腑
It just broke my heart.
-大家干得好  恭喜 -好...
- Well done, everyone! - Bravo! Bravo!
楚门喝尼加拉瓜山出产
由顶级可可炼制的莫可可
十七亿人见证他出生
1.7 billion were there for his birth.
巨星诞生
220个国家收看他学走路
220 countries tuned in for his first step.
举世静观他初吻
The world stood still for that stolen kiss,
他与科技并肩成长
And as he grew, so did the technology.
一个人的一生 由秘密摄影网络记录下来
An entire human life recorded on an intricate network of hidden cameras
原汁原味  一天二十四小时
And broadcast live and unedited 24 hours a day,
在全球不停直播
7 days a week to an audience around the globe.
桃源岛是一个
Coming to you now from seahaven island,
规模空前庞大的片场
Enclosed in the largest studio ever constructed
从太空俯瞰地球可以看到的
And along with the great wall of China,
唯有桃源岛和万里长城
One of only 2 manmade structures visible from space,
"真人表演"已经踏入
Now in its 30th great year,
光辉的第三十年
It's the Trueman show.
过去一个星期
What a week it's been.
高潮迭起  好戏连场
I don't know about you... I was on pins and needles the entire time.
各位观众好  我是麦克
Hello and good evening. I'm your host mike Michaelson,
欢迎收看"真人表演"的清谈节目"真话"
And welcome to tru-talk, our forum for issues growing out of the show.
今晚千载难逢
But tonight, something very special indeed,
会独家专访 "真人表演"的创作人
A rare and exclusive interview with the show's conceiver and creator.
我们上去天网摄制
So, come with us now as we go live to the lunar room,
221楼的太阴室
room on the 221st floor of the omni cam echosphere.
采访超级电视摄制的先驱
Where we'll find the world's greatest tele-visionary...
桃源岛的设计者和总监
The designer and architect of the world within a world
克里斯托
That is seahaven island... Christof.
我先代表观众
Before we begin, I'd like to thank you...
多谢你接受专访
on behalf of our audience for granting this interview.
我们知道你工作繁忙
We know how demanding your schedule is and...
一向作风都是尽量低调
we all know how jealously you guard your privacy.
能够采访你  我深感荣幸
This, sir, is indeed an honor.
不要客气
Don't mention it.
"真人表演"最近的一波三折
Well, the catalyst for the recent dramatic events...
起因是楚门的父亲偷偷回去
on the show has been Truman's father, Kirk.
外面的人擅闯桃源要接触楚门
And his attempts to infiltrate the show.
我们注意到
But before we get into that, I think it's worth noting
这并不是首次  对不对
That this is not the first time someone from the outside
但都是有惊无险
Has attempted To reach Truman, is it? we have had close calls in the past.
楚门  上电视了
Truman! It's television!
我终于上了"真人表演"
Yes! Yes! I did it! I'm on the Truman show!
但历来的擅闯事件中
But there's never been anything to compare.
最近这次最严重
With this most recent Breach in security...
因为擅闯的人是前任演员
The first intruder to be a former cast member.
而且本来已经死了
A dead one at that.
你让寇克复出  是神来之笔
Gotta say, writing Kirk back in... masterstroke.
既然这场风波由寇克引起
Since Kirk started this crisis in Truman's life,
我认为解铃还须系铃人
I came to the conclusion that only he could end it.
楚门...
Truman! Truman!
-不准过去  -那里有什么
- No! That's off limits! Why? - What's over there?
没什么  只是危险
Nothing. It's dangerous. That's all.
你要记着  有些地方不可以去
You've got to know your limitations, Truman.
当年为什么删除寇克这角色
but let's remind viewers exactly why Dad was written out in the first place.
楚门长大后
as Truman grew up,
我们设法把他留在桃源岛
we were forced to manufacture ways to keep him on the island.
我想做探险家  像麦哲伦一样
I'd like to be an explorer, like the great Magellan.
现在世上已没什么好探险的
You're too late. There's really nothing left to explore.
于是  我安排寇克淹死
Finally, I came up with Kirk's drowning.
那办法很有效  楚门从此怕水
Most effective. Truman's been terrified of the water ever since.
寇克被迫淹死  退出节目
When Kirk read the synopsis of the episode,
不得不说  他失望得很
He was disappointed to say the least.
于是千方百计潜回片场
Jesus! I'm sure that's what caused him to break onto the set.
但你怎么解释他失踪了二十二年
But how do you intend to explain his 22-year absence?
失忆
Amnesia.
高明
Brilliant.
现在接听观众电话
Let's take Some viewer phone calls.
北卡州的卡露莲  请说
Charlotte, North Carolina, You're on with Christof.
你好  克里斯托
Uh, yeah, Hi, Christof.
你在镇上布置了多少部摄影机
I was wondering how many cameras you got in that town.
五千部左右
Somewhere in the vicinity of 5,000.
好多
That's a lot of cameras.
记着  我开始时只用一部
Remember, we started with just one.
他一出生就好奇  早产两星期
He was curious from birth. Premature by 2 weeks.
就像迫不及待
Almost as if he couldn't wait to get started.
正因为他急于走出娘胎
His eagerness to leave his mother's womb.
所以才获选
Was the very reason he was the one selected.
我们从六个待领养胎儿中
In competition with 5 other unwanted pregnancies,
选出楚门  因为楚门...
The casting of a show, determined by an air date,
在现场直播中  准时出世
Truman was the one who arrived on cue.
楚门似乎是首名被机构
Incidentally, I believe Truman is the first child...
合法领养的孩子
to have been legally adopted by a corporation.
对
That's correct.
节目带来庞大的收益
The show has generated enormous revenues now,
相当于一个小国的年产总值
Equivalent to the gross national product of a small country.
但制作上
People forget it takes the population
也需要一国的人手
Of an entire country to keep the show running.
因为二十四小时播放  没广告时间
Since the show is on 24-hours a day without commercial interruption,
收入全靠商品的选用
all those staggering revenues are generated by product placement.
对  节目上一切都是发售的
That's true. Everything on the show is for sale.
演员的服装  食品  住屋等等
From the actor's wardrobe, food products, to the very homes they live in.
详情请参阅真人目录
And all of it available in the Truman catalog.
欢迎随时来电查询
Operators are standing by.
克里斯托  请问...
Christof, let me ask you,
为什么至今楚门还不知道
why do you think Truman has never come close...
自己活在一个什么样的世界
to discovering the true nature of his world until now?
我们都接受现实
We accept the reality of the world with which we are presented.
就是那么简单
It's as simple as that.
海牙有观众打电话来  海牙
The hague for Christof. Hello? The hague?
现在改接好莱坞的电话
All right, we've lost that call. Let's go to hollywood. You're on  tru-talk.
克里斯托  我只想说你好阴险
Hi, Christof. I'd just Like to say one thing. You're a liar and a manipulator,
你的所作所为令人恶心
And what you've done to Truman is sick!
我们都认得这声音  对吧
Well, we remember this voice, don't we?
怎么能忘记
How could we forget?
不如改接另一个电话
Let's go to another call.
不要紧  麦克
No, no, no. It's fine, Mike.
我想跟前任演员叙叙旧
I love to reminisce with former members of the cast.
西尔维亚
Sylvia...
你当众沷妇骂街  其实没意思
as you announced so melodramatically to the world,
你以为自己曾向楚门抛眉弄眼
You think because you batted your eyes at Truman once...
打情骂俏  曾和他一起出演过几场戏
flirted with him... stole a few minutes of air time with him...
就算得上很了解他
to thrust yourself and your politics into the limelight...
知道什么对他最好吗
That you know him? That you konw what's right for him?
知道什么才适合他
That you know What's right for him?
有资格去评论他
You really think you're in a position to judge him?
你有什么权力...
What right do you have to take a baby?
把一个人的一生  塑造成闹剧
And turn his life into some kind of mockery?
你一点也不觉得内疚
Don't you ever feel guilty?
我为楚门提供一个正常的人生
I have given Truman a chance to lead a normal life.
这个你所住的世界是病态的
The world... the place you live in... is the sick place.
桃源才是模范的世界
Seahaven's the way the world should be.
他不是演员  是囚犯
He's not a performer. He's a prisoner.
任由你摆布
Look at him! Look at what you've done to him!
他随时可以走
He can leave at any time.
假如他稍有野心
If his was more than just a vague ambition,
假如他下定决心要查出真相
If he was absolutely determined to discover the truth,
我们无法阻止他
There's no way we could prevent him.
你不安  其实另有原因
I think what distresses you really, Caller,
就是楚门甘愿坐你所谓的监狱
Is that ultimately... Truman prefers his cell, as you call it.
你错了
That's where you're wrong.
大错特错  他会证明你是错的
You're so wrong, and He'll prove you wrong.
观众甚少有恶评
Well, aside from The heated comments of a very vocal minority.
绝大部分都说它有益世道人心
It's been an overwhelmingly Positive experience.
对楚门  对观众  都有裨益
Yes. For Truman and for the viewing public.
克里斯托  万分感谢
Well, Christof, I can't thank you enough...
感谢你百忙中接受访问
for giving so generously of your time tonight.
现在危机已成过去
I think it's safe to say now that this crisis is behind us...
楚门恢复了常态
and Truman is back to his old self,
节目会不会有新发展
We can look forward to some exciting new developments?
未来的大事是
Well, mike, the big news...
在下一集  梅莉会离开楚门
is that Meryl Will be leaving Truman in an upcoming episode.
楚门将会有第二春
And a new romantic interest will be introduced.
我决定将他们亲密的过程
Aha. I'm determined television's first on-air conception...
首次在电视上直播
will still take place.
电视广播即将出现新的里程碑
Well, another television milestone straight ahead.
我们已率先为大家透露
You heard it here first.
十分感谢你
It has been a singular honor and pleasure, sir.
-克里斯托  -谢谢你  麦克
- Christof...thank you. - Thank you, Mike.
-西曼  -什么事
- Hey, Simeon. - What?
他是不是看着我们
Is he looking at us?
不得了  难道他看出了破绽
Jesus, do you think he knows?
你好
Hello?
我要通知克里斯托
Better call Christof.
报告  伯班克少校
Hello? Come in, major Burbank.
-他故态复萌  -天啊
- He's back to his old self. - Thank god.
好怪的猫
That's an unusual cat, my man.
谨此把本星球命名为...
I hereby... proclaim this planet...
伯班克银河系的楚门星
Trumania of the burbank galaxy.
-他要出去  -走廊镜头准备
- Is he going? - Hallway camera.
免费表演一次
That one's for free.
跟贴  他行动有点快
Keep up with him. He'll move fast.
全部摄影机准备
Stand by, All house cameras.
早安
Morning!
假如再碰不见你
Morning. In case I don't see you...
祝你早  午  晚都安
Good afternoon, good evening, and good night.
-午安  -早安
- Good afternoon. - Good morning.
午安  晚安
evening, And good night.
-早安  楚门  -早安  史宾沙
- Morning. - Morning, spencer.
-你好吗  -让我检查一下
- How's it going? - Hmm, let me check.
主要功能健全
Vital signs are good.
普鲁托
Whoa, pluto! Whoop!
-早安  楚门  -原来是你们
- Good morning, Truman! - Oh, look who's here.
-今天天气很好  -天天都这样好
- Beautiful day, isn't it? - Every single day.
我们决定向你买保险
The policy... We've thought about it... and we're gonna take it.
-说笑  -不是说笑
- You're kidding? - No!
好极  现在就上公司签文件吧
Great! Why don't we go up to my office right now, and we'll sign the papers?
下星期比较方便...
Uh, next week Would be much better. Next week would be better.
-那么到时见  -到时见
- All right. See you guys. - Ok, bye now. See you next week.
-约定你们了  -一言为定
- Give me something To look forward to. - You got it.
这不是保险的事
See, this isn't about insurance.
而是生死无常的事
This is about the great variable...
"几时死"
When will death occur?
一个星期  一个月  一年
Could be a week, a month, a year.
可能今天
Could be today.
你悠哉游哉的晒太阳
Sunbather, minding his own business,
一不留神  心脏被沙滩伞捅到
Stabbed in the heart by the tip of a runaway beach umbrella.
致命意外随时发生  防不胜防
No way to guard against that kind of thing.
对不起
Uh, sorry, excuse me.
楚门  这位是薇薇安  薇薇安  这是楚门
Uh, Truman, this is vivien. Vivien, this is Truman.
你们会经常见面
The two of you are gonna be neighbors.
我的意思是...
I guess what I'm...
生命脆弱
What I'm saying is that. Uh, life is... fragile.
-薇薇安  你的办公室  -对不起
- Vivien, your office. - Sorry.
什么  对不起
What's that? Oh, I'm sorry. Uh...
真的  好极了
You do? Oh, great.
我记下你的资料
Uh, let me take your information.
二号机准备  播二号
Ready 2. Go to 2.
再用中镜
And back to medium.
然后... 广镜
And wide.
我正想训练这小子...
I was just trying to train the kid to...
算了
Never mind.
他在地下室干什么
What's he doing in the basement?
梅莉走后  他搬了下去
He moved down there after Meryl packed up and left.
他有突发的举动  该向我报告
Why wasn't I told? Any unpredictable behavior has to be reported.
他在睡觉  我认为...
Uh, he... he's just sleeping, I thought.
可以看得清楚点吗
This the best shot we've got?
-你想看什么  -时钟摄影机呢
- What's to see? - What's on the clock cam?
被东西挡着
It's an obstruction... obstruction.
他在地下室做过什么
What happened down there?
收拾垃圾  我本想通知你
He was just tidying up his garbage. I was gonna call you.
但他没收拾完就睡着了
But halfway through he gave up, and he fell asleep.
我要检查明天的...
I wanna check on the setups for the...
明天的保险会
insurance convention tomorrow.
干得好
Nice move.
现在开始
There you go.
对准音响  拍摄他的身体
Isolate the audio. Give me a closeup on his torso.
有呼吸
He's still breathing.
寇莉  打电话给他
Where's chloe? Yes, sir. Call him.
-说些什么  -说打错了
- What do you want me to say? - Tell him it's a wrong number.
为什么那么久
What took you so long?
要轮候
Just had to wait for it.
客人多  你的
They were busy. Here.
-什么事  -不知道
- What's going on? - I don't know. They're...
他进房  站着  没做什么
He came down into the room. He did nothing but stand around for a while.
闭嘴  观察
Shut up and watch it!
然后我们就用夜镜
Then we went to nightvision.
他睡着了
[ring]He's asleep.
-这里  停  -什么事
- There! Stop it! - What?
-放大  -哪里
- Zoom in. - On which?
椅子下
Under the chair there.
加强清晰度
Enhance it.
-是不是... -不得了
- Is it... oh. - Oh, my god.
我...  他不可能在楼上
I...if... he couldn't have gone up the stairs.
一定在那里
I definitely... he must still be in the room.
-叫马龙去  -知道
- Get marlon Over there. - Right away.
楚门  有惊喜
Truman! Surprise party!
快来  老朋友
Oh. Come on, buddy.
六罐冰冻啤酒等待你我享用
I got a 6-pack of cold brewskis with our name on them.
你在哪里  还不出来
Come on, pal. Come on, buddy.
糟了
Shit.
马龙  找他  他还在房里
Marlon, find him. He's still in the room.
不要躲了  出来吧
Come out, come out wherever you are.
好  这语气就对了
That's good. Keep it light.
我知道你在这里  我会找到你
I know you're in here. I'm gonna find ya.
搜桌子下面
Check under the table.
你后面的衣柜
The closet, behind you.
他究竟在哪里
Gee. I wonder where he could possibly be.
草地镜头  用草地镜头
The lawn cam, get me the lawn cam.
不要看镜头  继续说话
Don't look in the camera. Say something.
继续  继续
Keep it going. Keep it going.
他走了
He's gone.
停播
Cut transmission!
Cut transmission?
停播
Cut it! Now!
有没有搞错
Jesus! God in heaven!
-漆黑一片  -把电话给我
- Everything's black. - Give me the phone.
技术故障  请稍候
所有配角都在搜索他
We've got every available extra looking for him.
主角也在帮忙
Uh, the principals are helping out.
台前幕后都出动  搜遍每一角落
The crew, too, so every sector's covered.
-道具车有没有少了  -没有
- What about prop cars? - Yes, they've been accounted for.
他必定走路
He has to be on foot.
全世界都认得他  他跑不掉
He has the world's most recognizable face. He can't disappear.
搜他出来...  乖狗
go. Hunt him. Hunt him. Yeah. Go find him, pluto. Good dog! Good dog!
大阵容
All this fuss.
他听到我的声音  就会出来
If he could just hear my voice.
楚门...
Truman! Truman!
我试试叫他
Let me try.
楚门  是爸爸  有事找我商量
Truman! It's me! Dad! Let's talk!
我知道
Yeah, I know.
我们搜过广场
Just about done with the square.
他一定在巴利摩处  回去搜吧
Got to go back to barrymore, Check the interiors. He's got to be in there.
巴利摩
Simeon: Barrymore, huh?
-学校呢  谁去  -不知道
- Uh-huh. But what about the college? Who's watching that? - I don't know.
-派人去吧  -知道
- Send somebody over there, ok? - All right.
立即带个人去
Take another man and get down there now, all right?
一定要把那杂种抓出来
I don't give a damn. Just find the son of a bitch.
拿电池来
Get some batteries.
黑漆漆怎么找到他
This guy's not gonna glow in the dark. Just get 'em down here.
什么事  接过来我这里
I don't know what's going on. Reroute it back to me.
太暗了  不可能找到他
We need more light. We'll never find him this way.
现在几点
What time is it?
现在太早了
It's way too early for that.
准备日出
Cue the sun.
真是的  现在几点了
Jeez! What time is it?
克里斯托  什么事
Christof, What's going on?
有传闻说他死了
Did you know that there's a rumor circulating that he's dead?
听到吗  记者蜂拥而至
You hear me? The media is having a feeding frenzy over this.
人人都打电话来
All the phone lines are jammed,
所有电视台都播
And every network has a pirated shot of marlon
马龙出丑镜头
Making an ass of himself in front of the camera.
赞助商威胁要取消合约
The sponsors are threatening to rip up their contracts.
取消  现在停播
Why? We're getting higher tatings with this graphic
收视率也很高
Than we've ever had on this show.
他无踪无影
No sign of him.
马龙  你回来  跟其他人会合
Why don't you head back to town and join the others?
大家留在原位  知道吗
Everyone else is at first positions, ok? Thank you.
大家留在原位了吗
Everyone's at first positions, right?
他一定还没走
We've got the light. So he's got to be there somewhere.
我们没有留意海面
We're not watching the sea.
为什么要留意海面
Simeon: hang on a minute. Why would we watch the sea?
搜索海港
Sweep the harbor.
启动海港摄影机  将镜头接到电脑
Bring up the harbor cameras. Shift all harbor cameras to computer, please.
有些摄影机失灵
Some of those are out, aren't they?
四部失灵  但灯塔那个有效
Yeah. We have 4 of them down, but we have the lighthouse cameras up.
-开动水上摄影机  -什么事
- All buoy cams, please. - What's happening?
-长镜  -为什么搜索水面
- ok. Long lens, short base cameras. - Why are we looking at the water?
好  移动它
Pan it, Will you, please?
楚门
Truman...
你去哪里
Where are you going?
他是做保险  怎么懂得驾驶船
How can he sail? He's in insurance.
他不怕水吗
Isn't he terrified of the water?
恢复播映
Resume transmission.
恢复播映中
Resuming transmission.
二赔一  我赌他溜不掉
hey, I want a piece of that 2 to 1 he doesn't make it.
车匙留在车内
Just leave 'em In the car.
别用船杆镜  看不见他的脸
Let's get off this mast shot. We can't see his face.
-用船舱镜  -船舱镜
- Go to the cabin cam. - Cabin cam.
好极了
There. Perfect.
拍到我们的英雄了
That's our hero shot.
派另一艘船出去
Let's get another boat out there.
吉士  我要跟码头的人通话
Ok. Listen, gus, I need you to talk to the guys on the ferry.
快点  快点出发
Come on. Get it moving. Get it out of here.
快些
Come on.
我只是巴士司机
I'm just a bus driver.
他们不懂得驾驶船
Bottom line is, they can't drive the boat.
他们都是演员
They're actors.
怎样截停他
How do we stop him?
好吧
Ok, uh...
开动风浪程式
We're going to be accessing the weather program now.
大家准备好
So hold on to your hats.
知不知道
You got that?
把风暴集中在船上
No. I think we're gonna want to localize the storm over the boat.
要对准船的位置
You can get the coordinates for that.
他没有救生艇  应付不来
There's no rescue boat. He won't know what to do.
他会害怕  会开回来
He'll turn back. He'll be too afraid.
风暴来了
There she blows.
启动掣
来吧
Come on.
闪电
Give me some lightning.
再闪
Again!
Hit him again!
收手  全世界都在看着
For god's sake, Christof, the whole world is watching.
不能让他当众死掉
We can't let him die In front of a live audience.
他当众出生
He was born in front of a live audience.
楚门
Truman!
你做得到的  加把劲
You can do it! Hold on!
你还有什么法宝
Is that the best you can do?
你想阻挡我  只有杀了我
You're gonna have to kill me!
-我命令你停播  -继续播
- On behalf of the studio, I demand that you cease transmission. - Keep running.
早晨遇到一个醉水手  问你怎么办
What shall we do with a drunken sailor early in the mornin'?
加强风力
Increase the wind.
Increase the wind!
我最后警告你
I'm telling you for the last time.
-有多接近  -很接近
- How close is he? - Very.
-吹翻他  吹他落海  -去你的
- Capsize him. Tip him over. - Damn you, Christof!
-他把自己绑着船身  -闭嘴
- You can't. He's tied himself to the boat! - Shut up!
他连淹死也不怕
He's gonna drown, and he doesn't even care.
吹翻他...
Do it. No. Do it!
够了
That's enough.
我想跟他谈谈
I want to talk to him.
出口
楚门
Truman.
你可以说话
You can speak.
我听得到你
I can hear you.
你是谁
Who are you?
我是创造者
I am the creator of a television show...
创造了一个 受万众欢迎的电视节目
that gives hope and joy and inspiration to millions.
那么  我是谁
Then who am i?
你就是那个节目的明星
You're the star.
什么都是假的
Was nothing real?
你是真的
You were real.
所以才有那么多人看你
That's what made you so good to watch.
楚门  听我说
Listen to me, Truman.
外面的世界...
There's no more truth out there...
跟我给你的世界一样的虚假
Than there is in the world I created for you.
有一样的谎言
The same lies.
一样的欺诈
The same deceit.
但在我的世界
But in my world...
你什么也不用怕
You have nothing to fear.
我比你更清楚你自己
I know you better than you know yourself.
你无法在我脑内装摄影机
You never had a camera in my head.
你害怕
You're afraid.
所以你不能走
That's why you can't leave.
楚门  不要紧  我明白
It's ok, Truman. I understand.
我看了你的一生
I have been watching you your whole life.
你出生时  我在看你
I was watching when you were born.
你学走路时  我在看你
I was watching when you took your first step.
你上学时  我在看你
I watched you on your first day of school.
还有你掉第一颗牙齿那一幕
The episode when you lost your first tooth.
你不能离开  楚门
You can't leave, Truman.
上帝  求求你
Please, god.
你属于这里
You belong here...
你可以走出去
You can do it.
跟我一起吧
With me.
回答我
Talk to me.
说句话
Say something.
说话  你在电视上
Well, say something, Goddamn it. You're on television.
正在向全世界直播
You're live to the whole world.
假如再碰不见你...
In case I don't see you...
祝你早  午  晚都安
Good afternoon, good evening, and good night.
他做到了 他做到了
He did it. He did it.
He did it! He did it!
他成功了  走吧  楚门
He made it! Yeah! All right, Truman!
停播
Cease transmission.
-还要一块吗  -不要了
- You want another slice? - No. I'm ok.
-还有什么节目  -看看还有什么
- What else is on? Where's the tv guide? - Let's see what else is on.